Preliminary Inventory to the Carl and Helen Winter Papers TAM.583
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
Carl and Helen Winter Papers
circa 1890-circa 2002
TAM.583
Tamiment Library / Wagner Archives
8.75 linear feet (10 boxes)
Carl Winter (1906-1991) and Helen Winter (1908-2001) were Communist Party USA activists and officials. Carl Winter was the Chair of the Communist Party of Michigan, was convicted in 1949 under the Smith Act of conspiracy to overthrow the government of the U.S. and served five years in prison, later became the editor of the Party's newspaper, The Worker. His wife Helen was herself a Smith Act defendant and daughter of Alfred Wagenknecht (1881-1956), a leading member of the Socialist Party, and later a charter member of Communist Party USA. The collection contains correspondence, including Carl Winter's prison correspondence, family correspondence including that of Alfred Wagenknecht with his wife Hortense and daughter; some documentation of the politiccal activity of Wagenknecht; clippings, most related to Carl Winter's Smith Act trial, and to the Winters' Michigan activism; Detroit Police Departments Red Squad files on Carl and Helen Winter; FBI files; speeches; Communist Party of Michigan printed ephemera; Allison family materials (the maternal branch of Helen's family); speeches, writings; interview transcripts; commemorative and memorial materials and memorabilia. See also the more detailed descriptions of the contents of each box.
Winter, Carl, 1906-1991
Historical/Biographical Note
Carl Winter (1906-1991) and Helen Winter (1908-2001) were Communist Party USA activists and officials. Carl Winter was the Chair of the Communist Party of Michigan, was convicted in 1949 under the Smith Act of conspiracy to overthrow the government of the U.S. and served five years in prison, later became the editor of the Party's newspaper, The Worker. His wife Helen was herself a Smith Act defendant and daughter of Alfred Wagenknecht (1881-1956), a leading member of the Socialist Party, and later a charter member of Communist Party USA. the Communist Party USA.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains correspondence, including Carl Winter's prison correspondence, family correspondence including that of Alfred Wagenknecht with his wife (Wagenknecht separated from his wife Hortense in 1930 and was finally divorced in January of 1948) and daughter; some documentation of the politiccal activity of Wagenknecht (he traveled to the Soviet Union on several occasions, served as the Executive Secretary of the National Committee to Aid Victims of German Fascism, and was the State Chairman of the Communist Party in Missouri from 1938 to 1941 and in Illinois from 1941 to 1945); clippings, most related to Carl Winter's Smith Act trial, and to the Winters' Michigan activism; Detroit Police Departments Red Squad files on Carl and Helen Winter; FBI files; speeches; Communist Party of Michigan printed ephemera; Allison family materials (the maternal branch of Helen's family); speeches, writings; interview transcripts; commemorative and memorial materials and memorabilia. See also the more detailed descriptions of the contents of each box.
Access Restrictions
Open for research without restrictions.
Separated Materials
Photographs separated from the collection to PHOTOS 286, including photographs and negatives from Alfred Wagenknecht's trip to China, photographs and negatives from Alfred Wagenknecht's trip in 1922 to London and Germany, a disbound scrapbook of Wagenknecht-Allison family photographs circa 1910-1930, photographs of Helen and Carl Winter from Communist Party events, photographs of labor activists and Communists including Carl and Helen Winter, Gus Hall, and Elizabeth Gurley Flynn, portraits of Alfred Wagenknecht, photographs from Winter's trips to Mongolia, East Germany, and other Soviet Bloc countries, photographs of Communist Party members like Elizabeth Gurley Flynn and Gus Hall, and photographs from the Mosley Demonstration (1948).
Communist Party of the United States of America (Mich.).; Wagenknecht, Alfred; Winter, Carl, 1906-1991; Winter, Helen, 1908-2001; Communism |z Michigan.; Communist trials |z United States.; Communists |z United States
- I, Biographical and Memorabilia
  - "A Life That Points The Way To The Future," People's Weekly World (Profile of Helen Winter), Sep 3, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - "A Message To Alison" (Hortense Allison), Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Allison, Elmer (Brother of Hortense): Obituary Of, Jul 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Allison, Elmer: Poems and Writings, 1921, 1943-1944 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Allison, Hortense (Mother of Helen Winter): Haymarket-Centered Memoir, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: Memorabilia, 1972, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Allison, Hortense: Memorials and Condolences For, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Allison, Hortense: Obituaries For, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Allison, Hortense: Portrait (Photocopy of Drawing by Kimberly Joy Estrada), Nov 1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Allison, Rose Rosen (Sister-in-law of Hortense Allison): "Do You Remember The Depression?", 1977 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Allison, Rose Rosen: "Elmer Allison - A Eulogy At Age 80", Dec 1963 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Allison, Rose Rosen: "Luftmensch In Yankeeland", Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Allison Machado, Gertrude (Sister of Helen Winter): Obituaries For, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: Genealogical Materials Collected By, 1905-2004 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: "Heartache and Heartbreak: Family Letters 1918-1931", 2000 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: "Our Puyallup Houses" (Compilation of Photographs), Jun 26, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: "Ozark Memories by Preston Johnson" (Compilation), 1973 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: "Poems By Elmer Allison", 1973 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Bus Schedules Used to Visit Carl Winter in Prison, 1950s (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Communist Party of Michigan: Welcome Back Celebration for Helen and Carl Winter, Dec 1983 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Communist Party USA: Gala Reception Honoring Carl and Helen Winter, Dec 1982-Feb 1983 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Communist Party USA: Lifetime Acheivement Award for Helen Winter, Mar 1996 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Communist Party USA Central Committee: Unique Contribution Award to Helen and Carl Winter, Aug 13, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Communist Party USA Political Bureau: Invitation to Farewell to Helen and Carl Winter, Oct 28, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Connecticut District Communist Party: 63rd Anniversary Celebration of the Communist Party USA (Tribute to Helen and Carl Winter), Dec 1982-Jun 1983 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Crockett, George: Remarks at Carl Winter Memorial (Audio Tape), Apr 5, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Daily World: Tribute for John Pittman and Carl Winter (Program), Apr 12, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Detroit City Council: Resolution In Memorium Helen Winter, Jan 25, 2005 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Johnson, Preston (Relative of Hortense Allison): "Pities Mr. Oswald" (Letter to the Editor), Nov 1963 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Machado, Eduardo (Brother-in-law of Helen Winter): Condolences and Obituaries For, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Manfred, Erica: "I Was a Red Diaper Baby," New York Times Magazine, Nov 2, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - People's Daily World: Certificate for Carl and Helen Winter, Jul 1, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Pettengill, Ryan: Consent Form For Detroit Oral Histories Project (Participant Unknown), Aug 6, 2008 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Plaja, Robert C. (Grandson of Hortense Allison): Memorials For, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Radio Moscow: Biography of Helen Winter (Russian Transcript and English Translation by Carl Winter), Circa 1956 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Tecla: To Women Mothers of the World (Artwork Inscribed to Helen Winter), 1983 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Condolences, Funeral Notices and Obituaries For, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Membership Card/State Constitution, Ohio Socialist Party, 1917-1919 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Memorabilia, Undated (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Passport, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Wagenknecht, Hortense: Membership Cards to Socialist Party of America and Workers Party of America, 1905-1914, 1924-1927 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Weissberg, Lily: Pictured in Clipping from May Day in Cleveland Plain Dealer, May 12, 1912 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Winter, Carl: Biography (Fragment), Undated (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Winter, Carl: Condolence Cards For, Nov 1991-Mar 1992 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Winter, Carl: Condolence Letters For, Nov 1991-Apr 1992 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Winter, Carl: Detroit Urban League Distinguished Warrior Plaque, Feb 14, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Winter, Carl: Memorial Service on April 5, 1992 (Includes Documents Illustrating His Career), Circa 1940-1992 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Winter, Carl: Obituaries For, Nov 1991-Apr 1992 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Winter, Carl: Oral History Included in Untold Tales, Unsung Heroes: An Oral History Of Detroit's African American Community (Detroit Urban League), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Winter, Carl: Oral History Transcript on Career as Communist Party Organizer in Michigan, Oct 5, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Winter, Carl and Claude Lightfoot: Internment Ceremony at Waldheim Ceremony, May 1992 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Winter, Helen: 85th Birthday Tribute in Detroit, Michigan (1), Dec 1992-Feb 1993 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Winter, Helen: 85th Birthday Tribute in Detroit, Michigan (2), Dec 1992-Feb 1993 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Winter, Helen: "A Glimpse Of The Past -- Working For The Future" (Draft of Article for People's Weekly World), Undated (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Winter, Helen: Condolences, Eulogy and Memorial Program For, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Winter, Helen: Get Well Message For, in People's Weekly World, Nov 17, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Winter, Helen: Memorabilia, 1950s-1980s (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Winter, Helen: Oral History with Joan Lockwood, et al.: Historical Chronology of Helen Winter's Life, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Winter, Helen: Oral History With Joan Lockwood et al.: Proofs of Text Based on Interviews, 1992-1993 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Winter, Helen: Oral History With Joan Lockwood et al.: Transcripts of Five Interviews with Revisions, Nov 1992-May 1993 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Winter, Michele: Commencement Program From Marygrove College, May 16, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 60)
- II, Correspondence
  - Allison, Gertude (Sister of Helen Winter): Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Allison, Hortense (Mother of Helen Winter): Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, Mar 1943-Aug 1946 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, 1952-1953 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, Mar 1959-Dec 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence with Families of the Smith Act Victims (Rose Perry), 1952, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Allison, Hortense: Letters to Wagenknecht, Alfred (Husband, Father of Helen Winter), 1924, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Allison, Hortense: Correspondence with Williamson, Mae, Sep 1952 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Allison, O.P. (Brother of Hortense Allison): Letter to Mother, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Allison, Ruth (Sister of Helen Winter): Letter to Wagenknecht, Alfred, Aug 1925 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Allison Walters, Judith: Letter to Winter, Helen, Jan 3, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Aptheker, Herbert: Letter to Winter, Helen, Mar 16, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Bachrach, Marian: Letter to Winter, Helen, 1952, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Christoffel, Ann: Letter to Patterson, William (Civil Rights Congress), Jun 26, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Columbus County Committee Communist Party, Ohio: Letter to the Winter Family, Dec 21, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Crane, Henry (Central Methodist Church): Letter to Winter, Carl, Dec 17, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Crockett, George: Letter to Winter, Carl and Helen Winter, Feb 4, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Davis, Benjamin: Letter to Winter, Carl, Circa 1956 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Hall, Arvo: Postcard to Winter, Michele, Undated (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Hall, Elizabeth: Letters to Winter, Helen, Dec 27, 1952, Sep 2, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Hall, Gus and Henry Winston: Letter to Allison, Hortense (Re: Lenin Centennial Memorial Medal), Mar 4, 1971 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Ishdorzh, S. (Mongolian People's Party): Letter to Winter, Carl, Mar 4, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Le Sueur, Meridel: Letter to Dennis, Peggy, Jul 13, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Licht, Mary: Letter to Winter, Helen, Oct 28, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - McKie, Bill: Letter to Winter, Helen, Dec 8, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Pomeroy, Bill: Letter to Winter, Helen (Re: Phillipines Communist Party), Feb 10, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Rubin, Daniel: Letter to Becchetti, Arnold, Undated (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Rust, Fritz: Letter to Winter, Carl, Mar 10, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - US Department of Justice, Bureau of Prisons: Letter to Allison, Hortense, Oct 7, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Gene (Sister of Helen Winter), Nov 1925, Apr 1926 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Letter to Allison, Gene, Gertrude Allison, Helen Allison, Ruth Allison (Daughters), Apr 29, 1926 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Gertrude, 1924, Undated (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Helen, Jul 1922, Jun 1924, Sep 1925 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense (Wife), 1922, Jan 1925-Jul 1925 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Aug 1925 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Sep 1925 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Oct 1925 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Nov 1925 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Dec 1925 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Jan 1926-Mar 1926 (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, Apr 1926-Aug 1926 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Correspondence with Winter, Carl and Helen Winter, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - Wagenknecht, Alfred: Postcards (in German), 1949-1951, Undated (Box 2, Folder 46)
  - Weissberg, Simon (Father of Carl Winter): Letter to Allison, Hortense, Sep 21, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 47)
  - Weissberg, Simon: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, 1951, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Alameda County Educational Committee of CPUSA (Homosexuality and Party Standards), Jun 1982 (Box 2, Folder 49)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Becchetti, Arnold (Re: Constitution Committee of CPUSA), Nov 29, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Diskin, Phil and Lou Bart, Oct 4, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 51)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Fred and Mary (Re: Peggy Dennis), Jul 20, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Haessler, Carl, Dec 10, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 53)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Hall, Gus, 1980-1986 (Box 2, Folder 54)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Jackson, James and Louis Weinstock, Jun 5, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Marshall, Scott (Labor Department of CPUSA), Jul 16, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 56)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Mensh, Harry, Sep 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 57)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Parry, Will (Re: Midwest Labor Institute), 1984-1985 (Box 2, Folder 58)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Rubin, Daniel (CPUSA), Nov 17, 1960, Oct 19, 1983 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Smith, Betty (International Publishers), Aug 2, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 60)
  - Winter, Carl: Speaking Engagements and Requests for Information, 1958-1964 (Box 2, Folder 61)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Stellato, Carl (Re: Commemoration of Ford Hunger March), Jan 6, 1959 (Box 2, Folder 62)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Teitelbaum, Kenneth (Re: Socialist Sunday Schools), Oct 1980 (Box 2, Folder 63)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Weissberg, Simon, Apr 7, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 64)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with West, Jim (Re: Party Standards), 1985-1986 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Williamson, John, Apr 25, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 66)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Winston, Henry, 1983, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 67)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Young Workers Liberation League, Jan 15, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 68)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence, Circa 1949-1955 (Box 2, Folder 69)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence, 1960s-1990s (Box 2, Folder 70)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Abt, John, 1952, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 71)
  - Winter, Helen: Letter to Allison, Gene, Hortense Allison, Ruth Allison, Undated (Box 2, Folder 72)
  - Winter, Helen: Letter from Ariyoshi, Koji (Hawaii Smith Act Defendant), Mar 10, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 73)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Barsky, Edward (National Committee to Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims), 1953 (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Begun, Isidore (National Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims), March 2, 1953-March 3, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 75)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Charney, Hattie (Families Of The Smith Act Victims), 1952, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 76)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Davis, Nina (Wife of Benjamin Davis), 1954, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 77)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Dennis, Peggy (Wife of Eugene Dennis), 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 78)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Gallacher, William, 1952, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 79)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Goodman, Ernest, Jul 18, 1953, Oct 19, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 80)
  - Winter, Helen: Letter to Goodman, William (Re: Death of Ernest Goodman), Apr 8, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 81)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Green, Abner (National Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims), Apr 1952-Feb 1953 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Green, Lillian (Chicago Committee To Win Amnesty For The Smith Act Victims), May 1952, Jun 1952 (Box 2, Folder 83)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley, Oct 2, 1949, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 84)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Haessler, Carl, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 85)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with House Un-American Activities Committee (HUAC), Aug 1962 (Box 2, Folder 86)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Johnson, Oakley C., 1963 (Box 2, Folder 87)
  - Winter, Helen et al.: Letter to Kissinger, Henry, Jul 3, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 88)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Le Sueur, Meridel, 1952, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 89)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Mackie, Toini (Includes Book of Poems, "Rhymes Of My Times"), Feb 1954, 1990s (Box 2, Folder 90)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Minneapolis Chapter Civil Rights Congress (Alma Foley; Includes Copy of Skit by Irene Paull on Arrest of Helen Winter), 1953, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 91)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with National Capital Area Civil Liberties Union/American Civil Liberties Union (Re: House Un-Americans Activities Committee Subpoena), Jul 1962 (Box 2, Folder 92)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Perry, Rose (Families of the Smith Act Victims), Jul 1952-Jun 1953 (Box 2, Folder 93)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, Jul 1951-Dec 1954 (Box 2, Folder 94)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Ross, Ken (Co-Producer, "1913 Massacre"), Mar 2001-May 2001 (Box 2, Folder 95)
  - Winter, Helen: Letter to Rubin, Danny (CPUSA), May 23, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 96)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with United States Immigration and Naturalization Service (Re: Gertrude Allison Machado), 1975 (Box 2, Folder 97)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Wayne State University Law School Repository (Re: Donation of Transcripts of United State vs. Dennis), Dec 1993 (Box 2, Folder 98)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Weissberg, Simon (Father-in-law), 1950-1955, Undated (Box 2, Folder 99)
  - Winter, Helen: Correspondence with Williamson, Mae, 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 100)
  - Winter, Helen: Holiday Cards, 1950s (Box 2, Folder 101)
  - Winter, Michele (Daughter of Carl and Helen Winter): Correspondence, 1950-1960 (Box 2, Folder 102)
  - Cassidy, David: Letter of Protest to Judge Harold Medina in Support of Carl Winter, Sep 16, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 103)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Abt, John, 1953-1957 (Box 2, Folder 104)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Bachrach, Marion, Jan 28, 1953, May 15, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 105)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Davis, Benjamin, Jul 30, 1951, Sep 5, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 106)
  - Crockett, George: Letter to Dennis, Eugene, Jul 30, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 107)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Gannet, Betty, Jan 19, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 108)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Green, Abner (American Committee for Protection of Foreign Born), Jan 1953-Feb 1953 (Box 2, Folder 109)
  - Crockett, George: Letter to Perry, Pettis, Jan 12, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 110)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Prison Authorities, 1951-1954 (Box 2, Folder 111)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Rabinowitz, Victor, Dec 1954-Feb 1955 (Box 2, Folder 112)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Stachel, Jack, Jul 1951-Sep 1951 (Box 2, Folder 113)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with United States Parole Board, Jan 1953-Mar 1953 (Box 2, Folder 114)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Williamson, Mae, Jan 28, 1953, Feb 19, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 115)
  - Crockett, George: Correspondence with Winter, Helen, 1951-1955 (Box 2, Folder 116)
  - Dave White Section (Detroit): Letter to Gurley-Flynn, Elizabeth (Re: Carl Winter's Birthday), Oct 1, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 117)
  - Flynn, Katherine (Relative of Elizabeth Gurley Flynn): Holiday Drawing for Carl Winter, Dec 1953 (Box 2, Folder 118)
  - Ganley, Ann: Letter to Winter, Carl, Oct 3, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 119)
  - Ganley, Patty: Letter to Winter, Carl, Oct 1949 (Box 2, Folder 120)
  - Gurley Flynn, Elizabeth: Correspondence with Winter, Carl, Circa 1949, Dec 1953 (Box 2, Folder 121)
  - Le Sueur, Meridel: Letter to Winter, Carl, Sep 1949 (Box 2, Folder 122)
  - McKie, Bill: Correspondence with Winter, Carl, 1949, 1953, 1954 (Box 2, Folder 123)
  - Williamson, John: Correspondence with Isserman, Abraham (Attorney), Mar 1952 (Box 2, Folder 124)
  - Winter, Carl: Birthday Cards (Received After Arrest), Sep 1949 (Box 2, Folder 125)
  - Winter, Carl: Birthday Cards, Sep 1951-Oct 1951 (Box 3, Folder 126)
  - Winter, Carl: Cards, 1951-1954, Undated (Box 3, Folder 127)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Abt, John, Sep 1951-Dec 1951 (Box 2, Folder 128)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense (Mother-in-law), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 129)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1952 (Box 2, Folder 130)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 131)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Allison, Hortense, 1954-1955 (Box 2, Folder 132)
  - Winter, Carl: Letter to Bennett, James (Bureau of Prisons), Jul 15, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 133)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George (Attorney), 1951 (Box 2, Folder 134)
  - Winter, Carl: Correspondence with Crockett, George, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 135)